Youngjoon Kim (김영준)

Seoul, South Korea

J +82-10-5008-8028

acorn421.github.io in linkedin.com/in/acorn421 github.com/acorn421

Summary

I am a captain of the R.O.K. Army and a Ph.D. student at Korea University. I have experience in both security research and security engineering while working at ADD and R.O.K. Cyber Operations Command. Throughout my career, my main focus has been the integration of AI and security. In particular, I would like to apply AI to offensive security. To this end, academically, I am interested in AI-assisted fuzzing. Practically, I am interested in AI-assisted penetration testing. Recently, I started researching on finding vulnerabilities in smart contracts.

Work Experience

R.O.K. Cyber Operation Command

Oct. 2022 - Present

Security Engineer

Seoul, Korea

- Performed vulnerability assessments for R.O.K. military IT infrastructure.
- Worked as a **red team** during R.O.K. military cyber operation exercises.
- Conducted cybersecurity management ability assessment for public institutions in South Korea.
- Keywords: Red team, Web hacking, Reverse engineering, Binary exploitation, APT attack
- Frameworks/Tools: Metasploit, Burp suite, IDA, WinDBG, Cobalt strike, Nmap, Python, C/C++, Powershell

Agency For Defense Development

Jul. 2017 - Sep. 2022

Security Researcher

Seoul, Korea

Research on National-level cyberattack defense technologies

Jan. 2021 - Sep. 2022

- Goal: Organize adversaries' cyberattack operations into attack chains, categorize them into appropriate campaigns, and respond automatically to disrupt the attacker's ultimate goals.
- Researched predicting the next attack using Bayesian network and MITRE ATT&CK.
- Implemented network-level and host-level automatic defense using SDN.
- Keywords: APT Attack, Automatic response, MITRE ATT&CK, Bayesian Network, SDN
- Frameworks/Tools: MITRE ATT&CK, bnlearn, ONOS
- Language: Python, R, Javascript

Research on techniques for evaluating binary fuzzing results

Jan. 2018 - Oct. 2020

- Goal: Develop techniques to analyze and evaluate crashes generated from software fuzzing to identify root causes and automatically assess whether they could lead to vulnerabilities.
- Developed Linux-based taint analysis tool for Windows x64.
- Introduced crash triage technique using additional directed fuzzing and taint analysis.
- Keywords: Fuzzing, Crash triage, Crash prioritization, Root cause analysis, Dynamic binary instrumentation, Taint analysis
- Frameworks/Tools: WinAFL, libdft, WinDBG, Pintool, Dynamorio, Valgrind
- Language: Python, C/C++, Javascript

Research on cyber threat analysis and countermeasures for warship systems

Jul. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Conducted threat analysis and proposed countermeasures for R.O.K. navy warship information systems based on NIST standards.
- Keywords: Threat analysis, Risk management, NIST SP 800-53, NIST SP 800-37, NIST SP 800-30

Plain Bagel, Inc

Full Stack Developer(Part-time)

Mar. 2015 – Feb. 2017

Seoul, Korea

Slidee: Platform for editing and sharing YouTube video stills

- Built a web-based editor to convert YouTube videos into screenshots with captions.
- Built a web platform to share user-generated content.
- Implemented an ELK-based user and service statistics analysis server.
- Optimized cloud hosting and databases for reliable service and cost optimization.
- Framework/Tools: React, Redux, Express.js, MongoDB, ELK stack, AWS, Google Analytics
- Language: Python, Javascript, Node.js

Mar. 2015 - Feb. 2017

Education

Korea University

Sep. 2018 – Present

Seoul, Korea

Korea University

B.S. in Cyber Defense

Mar. 2013 - Feb. 2017

Seoul. Korea

Hansung Science High School

Ph.D. in Information Security

 $Mar.\ 2011-Feb\ 2013$

Seoul, Korea

Publications

• SCVMON: Data-oriented attack recovery for RVs based on safety-critical variable monitoring. Sangbin Park, Youngjoon Kim, and Donghoon Lee International Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions, and Defenses (RAID), 2023

• BAN: Predicting APT Attack Based on Bayesian Network With MITRE ATT&CK Framework. Youngjoon Kim, Insup Lee, Hyuk Kwon, Gyeongsik Lee, and Jiwon Yoon IEEE Access, 2023

• A new approach to training more interpretable model with additional segmentation.

Sunguk Shin, Youngjoon Kim and Jiwon Yoon

Pattern Recognition Letters, 2021

• Maxafl: Maximizing code coverage with a gradient-based optimization technique.

Youngjoon Kim and Jiwon Yoon

Electronics, 2020

Domestic Patents

• DEVICE AND METHOD FOR DATA-ORIENTED ATTACK DETECTION AND RECOVERY FOR ROBOTIC VEHICLES BASED ON SAFETY-CRITICAL VARIABLES MONITORING.

Sangbin Park, Youngjoon Kim, and Donghun Lee

Korean Patent 10-2023-0157140(application number), In review

• SOFTWARE TAINT ANALYSIS METHOD AND SOFTWARE TAINT ANALYSIS DEVICE USING THE SAME.

Kyeongsik Lee, Youngjoon Kim, Younggi Park, and Hojun Lee

Korean Patent 10-2344497-0000, 2021

Other Experiences

1-day Vulnerability Analysis

Apr. 2019 - Nov. 2021

Student Intern

Sponsored by Korea University

- Wrote a 1-day vulnerability analysis report and implemented proof-of-concept code as a Metasploit module.
- Framework: Metasploit, Django
- Language: Ruby, Python

SW Maestro

Jun. 2015 – Dec. 2015

Developer

Sponsored by Ministry of Science and ICT

Matnam

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2015

- Advertisement application for local restaurants through Instagram.
- Framework: Android SDK, Google Cloud, Google App Engine
- Language: Java

Random Routing Mutation

Jun. 2015 - Aug. 2015

- Network security systems using SDN technology.
- Framework: ONOS, Mininet
- Language: Java

Student Intern

Android Malware Anlaysis

Mar. 2014 - Dec. 2014

Sponsored by KISA

• Decompiled a real malicious Android app and analyzed its malicious behavior.

• Framework: JEB Decompiler

• Language: Java

SGen club Jul. 2012 – Jun. 2014

Developer

Sponsored by Samsung SDS

ENTOP: Entertainment Top 10

Jan. 2014 – Jun. 2014

• Website that recommends the BEST 10 based on user interests.

• Framework: Django, jQuery, MySQL

• Language: Python, Javascript

MIV Jul. 2013 – Dec. 2013

• Application that automatically recognizes the video's music and provides music information.

• Framework: Android SDK, MySQL

• Language: Java

LOVIE: MOVIE+LOVE

Jan. 2013 - Jun. 2013

• Movie recommendation and review application for couples.

• Framework: Android SDK, MySQL

• Language: Java

MonsterAlarm Jul. 2012 – Dec. 2012

• Alarm application with game mechanics and nurturing concepts.

• Framework: Android SDK, sqlite

• Language: Java

Skills

Programming Languages: Proficient - C/C++, Python, Java, Occasional - Java, JavaScript, Node.js, R, Solidity, Rust Cloud Platforms: AWS, Google Cloud

Frameworks/Tools: AFL, Pintool, Burp suite, IDA, WinDBG, PyTorch, TensorFlow, React, Git, MongoDB